NIVEDITHA RAMU

CONTACT

Phone:+31-0618421361

Email: niveditharamu. 54@gmail.com

Linkedin:www.linkedin.com/in/nived

itha-ramu

Github: https://github.com/NIVEDITH

<u>A54</u>

CORE SKILLS

Programming Languages: Core Java

Database: MSSQL,ORACLE

ORM tool: Hibernate

Application Framework: Spring Boot

Devops technologies: Docker

Web designing: HTML5, CSS3,

JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap5, React

Application server: Jboss, IBM Websphere

OS: Windows, Linux

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

BE in Computer Science & Engineering 2014-2018

National Institute of Engineering

Mysore, India (Secured 9.3 CGPA)

SUMMARY

Diligent Full Stack developer with 3+ years of experience in frontend and backend technologies. Adept in troubleshooting performance bottlenecks and technical issues with strong understanding of Java, SQL database , Frontend technologies and application server.

WORK EXPERIENCE

☐ Full Stack Developer

Match4markets, Leiden, Netherlands | July 2021-present

Responsibilities:

- Building stable and maintainable code bases using React.
- Building features on the existing websites.
- Collaborating with the designer to ensure designs are efficient and technically sound.
- Developing HTML email templates and newsletters for marketing campaigns.
- Performing bug fixes and code review.
- Conducting A/B testing to identify bugs and UI improvements.
- Improved the performance of the MSSQL database.
- ☐ Java Software Engineer

Infor , Barneveld , Netherlands | *June 2021-June 2021*

ION Platform Development Team

Responsibilities:

- Involved in various phases of SDLC of the application like Requirement gathering, Design, Analysis and Code development.
- Developed a feature to get the information about the integrated ION processes in a multitenant cloud platform.
- Maintenance and support of Co-ordinator module.

☐ Software Engineer

Temenos, Bengaluru, India | July 2018-Jan 2021

Application Specialist Group | *June 2019-Jan 2020*

Responsibilities:

- •Expertise in handling critical production calls COB crashes, online performance etc.
- •Go Live Support and Financial Year end support team.

Offshore support team | *July 2018 – May 2019, Feb 2020-Jan 2021*

Responsibilities:

- Technology framework team troubleshooting and identifying feasible solutions for the technical issues which maintains integrity of the business.
- Provide support in enterprise application deployment.
- Perform code analysis, replication of the issue and move the issues identified as bugs to maintenance.
- Troubleshooting performance bottlenecks in different layers of architecture.
- Develop tools to assist in troubleshooting.

Tools developed:

1. vocUpdater Tool

Dec 2018-Feb2019 | Technologies : Java, JDBC

- The tool helps in finding the mismatch between the type of the application tables created in database and its entry in master table. It stores the mismatched data in excel sheet for easy analysis.
- The tool also provides the provision to correct the found mismatches and works on MSSQL,ORACLE and DB2 environments.

2. MW42 tool

March 2019 - May 2019 | Technologies : Java

• This tool writes the Lock stack, Call stack and the related details of the session into the csv file. It is mainly used to monitor system and analyze performance issues.